字幕翻译/压制：旋火
视频来源：youtu.be/GUzDTV1JEWQ
原视频发布日期：20200225
原作者名：Scott Manley
大家好 我是Scott Manley
Hello, it's Scott Manley here.
18个月前的视频：youtu.be/LlsZysPeidI
大约18个月前 我透露了Astra 这个神秘的火箭创业公司的细节
About 18 months ago, I revealed details of this stealth rocket startup called Astra.
他们在旧金山湾区的中心制造火箭
They were building rockets in the middle of the San Francisco Bay Area.
在这个被互联网科技公司包围的地方
In a part of the world surrounded by Internet tech companies,
他们在阿拉米达海军旧基地建造了一个小型卫星运载火箭
they were building a small Sat launch vehicle in the old Alameda Navy base.
如果一切顺利的话
If all goes well,
他们应该很快就会进行首次入轨发射
they should be making their first launch to orbit very soon
作为所谓的DARPA快速发射挑战的一部分
as part of something called the DARPA rapid launch challenge.
所以DARPA发射挑战的目的是发展快速反应发射能力
So the DARPA launched challenge aims to develop rapid response launch capability.
任务是发射一个航天器 只需提前几周通知
The task is to launch a spacecraft given just a few weeks of notice
而不是考虑到通常与其发射计划相关的年份
instead of given the years typically associated with their launch plans.
这将让该团队净赚200万美元的奖金
That would net the team a prize of two million dollars
但不仅仅是这些
but that's not the end of things.
假设这次发射没问题
Assuming this works,
然后 他们将有机会在几天内从另一个发射场进行第二次发射
they would then have the chance to perform a second launch from another site within days
而这将使他们净赚1000万美元
and that will net them a cool 10 million dollars.
现在 最初的计划是
Now originally the plan was
他们会在世界的两个不同地方有两个不同的发射场
they would have two different launch sites in two different parts of the world.
但现在看来 两个发射场
But now it looks like both launch sites
都将在科迪亚克导弹发射场 虽然相隔300米左右
will be at the Kodiak Missile Range albeit about 300 metres apart.
最关键的是运载火箭本来就不需要专门的发射台
The key thing was the launch vehicles weren't supposed to require a dedicated pad.
原本宣布了三家入围企业
Originally there were three finalists who were announced
他们是矢量空间系统 维珍轨道 以及没名字的第三家公司
and they were Vector Space Systems, Virgin Orbit and an unnamed third team
但当然 已经有聪明的人(指Scott Manley自己)猜到了
but of course the smart people out there is speculated
是Astra 这一点很快得到了其他相关团队的证实
that it was Astra and that was quickly confirmed by other teams involved.
自此 维珍轨道公司退出了
Since then Virgin orbit withdrew.
Vector已经破产
Vector has gone bankrupt.
只有Astra留下来作为唯一的竞争对手
Leaving Astra as the old only competitor.
当这一切发生时 Astra还是个秘密
Now when this happened Astra was still secret
但在2月初 他们终于上市了
but at the start of February they finally went public.
他们是在旧金山湾区举行的小卫星座谈会的一个主要赞助商
They were a major sponsor at the small SATs symposium conference in the San Francisco Bay Area
你知道那是他们的市场 他们想(把发射服务)卖给小型的卫星制造商
and you know that was their market they want to sell to small Sat builders
所以他们请了很多人到他们的工厂 开了派对
so they bust a lot of people up to their factory, had the party,
给他们一些食物 并试图出售他们的火箭
gave them some food and tried to sell them on their rocket
据我们所知 它其实没有名字
which as far as we can tell doesn't actually have a name.
它只是火箭
It's just the rocket.
这差不多是一个12米高的火箭
It's like a 12 meter tall launcher.
它使用五个发动机 使用电动驱动燃料泵
It uses five engines that are using electrically driven pumps.
根据视频显示 这些发动机产生了140kN的推力
According to the video they generate a total of 140 kilonewtons
所以每个发动机推力大概为28千牛顿
so that would be 28 kilonewtons.
相比之下 火箭实验室电子火箭上的那些卢瑟福发动机产生24kN的推力
For comparison, the rocket labs electron those Rutherford engines generate 24 kilonewtons.
当我18个月前做视频时
When I did my video of 18 months ago,
他们说的是40kN的推力 所以这其实有点下降
they talked about like 40 kilonewtons of thrust so this is a bit of a step down
但这样的推力也应该足以推动他们的火箭
but it should be more than enough to lift their launch vehicle.
另外在我之前的视频中
Also in my previous video,
我看了他们的各种政府拨款的申请材料 其中表明
I had looked at various filings for grants that they had and suggest that
他们可能会考虑使用差动油门来引导火箭的方向
they might be considering using differential throttle to steer the rocket
而这本来是一个非常酷的创新
and this would have been a really cool innovation.
然而 他们现在绝不会这样做
However, it they're definitely not doing that.
很明显 他们在这些火箭上安装了传动装置
It's very clear that they have actuators on these rockets
他们能够对发动机进行方向调节
that they are able to gimbal the motors.
这幅画面显示 他们实际上是
If you look at the pictures, then they're actually
在火箭喷嘴周围装上了某种耐热纤维
they have the like heat-resistant fabric around the rocket nozzles
让他们可以移动 从而控制和引导火箭
allowing them to move and therefore control and steer the rocket.
我现在还不确定第二级的情况
I'm not sure about the second stage at this time.
合理地推测 它只是一级发动机的复制品
It would seem logical to presume that it's just a copy of the first stage engines.
但采用了真空优化的喷管
But with a vacuum optimized nozzle.
箭体结构是铝制的
The structure is all aluminium.
看起来一级像是共底的
It looks like the first stage has a common bulkhead.
它以煤油和液氧为动力
It runs on kerosene and liquid oxygen.
顶部的整流罩上有软木涂层
The fairing at the top has cork coating on it.
整个装置可以装在一个集装箱里
And the whole thing fits inside a shipping container
这很有意思
which is you're really interested
因为你可以看到这个集装箱被从飞机上卸下来了
because you see this shipping container being unloaded from a plane
之后在另一段视频里 你看到他们
and then later you see the team put on another video.
正在集装箱里进行有效载荷的总装
You see the team performing payload integration inside this containers.
就像是里面设置了一个有效载荷总装设施
was like almost set up like a payload integration facility.
这次测试发射的有效载荷是三个小立方星
The payload of this test launch are three small cube sets.
一个叫普罗米修斯
One called Prometheus.
一个叫ARCE 另一个叫SOARS
One called ARCE and the other called SOARS.
自行搜索urban dictionary
当我看到这俩写一块的时候 我得到了一个很糟糕的解释
And when I saw those written down, I had a terrible terrible interpretation
但是 是的 这些都会是他们的有效载荷
but yeah those are gonna be their payloads.
正如我所说 没有永久的发射台 有一个发射结构
As I said there's no permanent Launchpad, there's a launch structure.
你可以看到导焰装置和点火设备
You can see with flame diverters and ignition hardware.
还有各种加注燃料的设备
There's various cards for loading fuel onto it
以及支撑结构 这些都是可移动的
and you support structures that are all mobile.
发布会原计划于周二进行
The launch was originally planned for Tuesday
但看起来因为天气影响 最早也要推到周四了
but it looks like weather has pushed it out to the Thursday at the earliest.
虽然火箭的设计并没有一个超越Astra3.0的名字
While the rocket design doesn't have a name beyond Astra 3.0,
这个特定的火箭被称为三枚中的一枚
this specific vehicle is called one of three.
其理由是
The justification being that
他们认为成功的机会只有三分之一
they think there's a one in three chance of a being successful
或者说 通常需要三次发射才能让这东西运转起来
or rather than it usually takes three launches to get this thing going.
我猜测三次中的一次是指
And I'm presuming the one of three implies that
这还不包括他们在极度保密的情况下 试图从科迪亚克进行的前两次发射
that doesn't include the previous two launches they attempted from Kodiak, under great secrecy.
众所周知 这两次发射都是为了发射亚轨道火箭
It was known the both of these launches were intended to be suborbital launchers,
用载荷模型来测试第一级
testing the first stage with a dummy payload.
但在火箭成功升空之前 都失败了
But both of them failed even before they could leave the facility.
我听说第一次发射失败的原因是引擎舱起火了
I've heard that the first launch failed after a fire started in the engine bay
并基本上烧毁了所有的线缆以及燃料泵泵
and essentially burned through all the wiring to their pumps
而火箭摔回了地面
and the vehicle fell back to earth.
第二次则是有一对发动机的故障
The second one, there were a pair of engine failures
然后将它们全部关闭 再次坠毁
and then that shut them all off and again it fell back to earth.
我可以肯定的是 它们都在发射场的范围内失败了
What I do know for sure is that they both fail within the confines of the launch site
这意味着 他们实际上不得不进行清理
which meant that they actually had to perform cleanup
因为在这个区域里倾倒了大量的煤油燃料
because of the large amount of kerosene fuel that was dumped in the area
他们不得不运出数百吨的污物进行处理
they had to ship out hundreds of tons of dirt to be treated.
他们通过特别的设备来清除这些碳氢化合物
What they do to remove these hydrocarbons is ticketed for facility
首先是使碳氢化合物汽化
that will heat it up the hydrocarbons vaporize
然后通过高温催化剂将其分解成二氧化碳
and then they have a high temperature catalyst that breaks it down into carbon dioxide.
我们之所以知道这个
And we know about this
是因为有必须要记录下来官方的报告
because there were official reports that had to be filed to document this.
所以不管怎么说 虽然这些火箭并没有像预期的那样飞得很远
So anyway while these vehicles didn't fly as far as expected,
他们的网站确实声称这两次发射都很成功
their website does claim that these launches were both successful.
而且说实话 我希望他们的下一次发射能够成功
And honestly I'm hoping that they will be successful in the next one.
他们认为他们已经从这些失败中吸取了教训
They think they've learned from these failures
他们认为他们下次成功入轨的可能性很高
and they will have a pretty good chance of putting this next launch into space.
而这实际上是一个相当有趣的转变
And it's actually been quite an interesting turn around.
他们已经从完全保密的状态
They've gone from complete stealth.
真·保密
You know hiding everything.
没放出过太多消息
There's not a lot of stuff out there.
DARPA的发射挑战每天都有视频发布
The DARPA launch challenges having videos posted every day.
(Astra公司的)CEO Chris Kemp在推特上说
The CEO Chris Kemp has said on Twitter that
他们正在准备发射的直播
they're working on a live stream for the launch.
他们邀请了我的好友John Krause 专业火箭摄影师
They've invited my buddy John Krause, professional rocket photographer
我敢肯定他能拍得尽可能震撼
who I'm sure will make these things look as amazing as they can be.
所以我们等着瞧吧
So I guess we're gonna see what happens.
这会比以前更公开
You know much more publicly than before.
现在看一下我们已经看过的 这次发射挑战之外的视频
Now looking beyond this launch challenge the videos that we've seen.
他们展示了许多已经在生产中的火箭
They show many many Rockets already in production.
有不少产品已经接近发射状态
Multiple units that are getting are near to flight ready.
所以实际上他们是在以相当快的速度生产火箭
So they are actually turning these things out at quite a rate.
根据CEO的说法 他们已经有16次发射的计划
According to the CEO they have maybe 16 launches already planned and manifested
而这种火箭应该是非常便宜的
and the launch vehicles are supposed to be very very cheap.
在一次采访中 他们说到了成本的线索
And one of the clues to the cost is that in one interview they talked about
第一枚火箭的碳纤维整流罩的价格
the cost of a carbon-fiber nose corner in the first vehicle
差不多25万美元
being about a quarter of a million dollars
就已经接近于整个火箭的成本了
and that was close to the cost of the entire vehicle.
所以他们很有理由相信
They're far as reasonable to assume
每个卫星的发射价格不会超过25万美元
that they're not looking at more than a quarter of a million dollars per launch vehicle
而一次专用的发射价格将是250万美元左右
and the cost of a dedicated launch would be something like two and a half million dollars.
而这将是高达200公斤的有效载荷
And that would be up to two hundred kilograms of payload.
你可以在他们的网站上预订未来的发射
They have a website where you can book potential future launches.
基本上就是把你想要发射载荷送入指定轨道
You know you could basically put in which orbit you want.
以及具体是怎样的载荷 然后他们会告诉你什么时候会进行发射
You know and what kind of payloads and they'll tell you when that launch opportunity is.
所以实际上有两类轨道
So there's actually two classes of orbit
太阳同步轨道 将从阿拉斯加的科迪亚克发射
that they're offering they're offering Sun Synchronous Orbit that will be from Kodiak in Alaska.
而9度倾角的轨道估计就是夸贾林环礁
There's a 9 degree orbit possibility and that I think is Kwajalein at all.
我想说这是一件好事
And I'm gonna say it's a good thing.
所有的发射硬件都是如此简单且可移动
That all that launch hardware is so easy and mobile
因为这两个发射场可能是最偏僻的两个美国发射场
because those two launch sites are probably the two least accessible launch sites that are run by the US.
还有另外几个发射场在范登堡和沃洛普斯
There's another couple of launch sites that were mentioned at Vandenberg, Wallops
和圣尼古拉斯 你可能没听说过这个名字
and San Nicholas which you've probably never heard of.
但显然可以从一个岛上发射卫星
But apparently is possible to launch satellites from an island.
就在你知道的范登堡以南地区的海岸线附近
Just off the coast of you know the region south of Vandenberg.
已经GG了
但现在我们希望天气良好 发射顺利
But for now we're hoping for good weather and good flight.
我是Scott Manley
I'm Scott Manley.
切记 注意飞行安全
Fly safe.